Sergio Villarroel

Full Stack Software Engineer

⊠ sergioworking247@gmail.com 🍪 +1 707-4409693 →54 911-58095853 🍙 www.sergiovilladev.com 😡 github.com/sergiov13

Engineer with of Software and Web experience. years of I've been involved every step software methodologies development implementing agile and while scrum generating extensive of documentation features, previous experiences knowledge and skills that allow me to effectively communicate remotely with team members and clients from startups and middle sized companies to achieve goals and customer satisfaction.

Relevant Experience

Sr Full Stack Software Engineer @ FreightFlow

April 2023 - March 2024 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Implemented multiple Backend API Models, Migrations, ES Indexes and Services with Python, Flask, FastAPI, SQLAlchemy, Alembic, Elastic Search with their respective Front end Views with React and Redux.
- Refactored and created revamped docker environments to improve deployment, stability and upgrade dependencies.
- Worked closely with team members on handling downtimes, improving security and performance.

Sr Backend Software Engineer @ NaNLabs

May 2022 - April 2023 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Designed, tested and deployed an ETL Data Lake and workflow for joining and enriching multiple data sources implementing python, Docker, Spark, MongoDB, Serverless Framework and AWS Services (Glue, Lambda, EC2, DocumentDB).
- Designed and developed simple Django and Flask APIs for displaying and reviewing data.

Ssr Full Stack Software Engineer @ Newfold Digital

Aug 2021 - May 2022 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Refactored a classic wordpress marketplace from a monolith to a Micro-Service based platform improving response time, deployment times and all around stability.
- Designed, built and implemented an API Gateway, Kubernetes Cluster and micro-services which were then deployed to AWS services.

Web Developer @ Freelance

April 2020 - Aug 2021 // Sacramento, CA

- Wrote modern, performant and robust code for a diverse array of clients and internal projects, while communicating and collaborating with multi/ disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, clients on a daily basis.
- Worked with a variety of different languages, frameworks and content management systems such as JavaScript, React, Django, Node.JS. Python, Selenium, etc.

Java Developer & QA Developer @ Accenture

May 2017 - April 2020 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Lead a small team focused on developing a testing tool based in python and Selenium web Driver which applied a light layer of Machine Learning and Database feedback for testing new implementations automatically.
- Modified existing software of Oracle's CCB application using Java,
 Hibernate and spring to correct bugs along with improving performance and upgrading interfaces.
- Worked closely with PM in successfully migrating and backing up databases, restoring and updating the billing application for a major Argentinian energy company.

SAP Consultant @ IBM

May 2014 - December 2016 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Advised clients regularly regarding projects, proposals, and technical issues that arise during the development process, while collaborating with other team members to determine the best design specifications and application of solutions.
- Designed, mapped and developed internal workflows for legal, planning and confidential documents, and developed a file management system with ABAP.

Skills

Programming Languages

Python, Javascript (ES6), Typescript, GraphQL, MySQL, BigQuery, HTML, Bash, Shell Scripting, PostgresSQL, MongoDB, DocumentDB, YAML, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform.

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Vue, Redux, Gatsby, NextJS, Node.JS, Express, Flask, FastAPI, SQLAlchemy, Alembic, Django, RabbitMQ, Redis, Celery, JWT, OAuth, Spring, Hibernate, Selenium, Serverless, pySpark, TensorFlow, Pytest, Jest, Cypress.

Tools & Platforms

Git, Webpack, Netlify, AWS, GCP,
Firebase, Docker, Trello, Jenkins,
Windows and Linux.

Education

UADE

(Argentinian University of Business) 2016 - 2023 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Courses

Automation with Python (by Google).

AWS Services for Data.

QA Testing of software solutions.

Advanced Java (Threads, 00,
Servlets).

Hibernate, Java EE, JSP, JSF.

Maven Web Applications.

Projects

Music Rooms:

Web App built with Django, React and spotify API where you can create and join a room with a unique code and vote for next song or to skip songs.

Interests

Photography, Outdoor activities, Reading, Traveling and new technologies.

Languages

English (Native) Spanish (Native)